The Gilbert and Lila Silverman Fluxus Collection Archives
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series I: Artists, Personalities, and Groups, 1952-2012
  - William Louis Sørenson, 1969; Mailings to Arthur Køpcke. (Box 70, Folder I.1148)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1970-1971; Posters/exhibition announcements from Eat Art Gallery, Dsseldorf. Inventory #s: 05702.1-2, 05699, 05698, 05696 (Box 70, Folder I.1149)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1966-1977; Exhibition and publication announcements; correspondence, including to Arthur Køpcke, Knud Pedersen, Ken Friedman, Jonas Mekas. Inventory #s: 05697.1-3, 05706, 05693, 05705, 05704.1-2, 05695, 05707.1-2, 05710 (Box 70, Folder I.1150)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1963; 2 copies of program and menu with reservation card for 723 Ustensiles de Cuisine, event at La Galerie J., Paris, mailed to Arthur Køpcke. Inventory #s: 05691 (Box 70, Folder I.1151)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1975-1975; Photocopies of correspondence to Maciunas from the Jean Brown Archive. Inventory #s: 05708.1-7b (Box 70, Folder I.1152)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1962-1994; Material collected on Daniel Spoerri, including photocopy of "Attention, Work of Art!" newspaper article by Emmett Williams in The Stars and Stripes(1962). Inventory #s: 05709.1-2b (Box 70, Folder I.1153)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1960-1961; 2 photographs of snare pictures by Daniel Spoerri, one with note by Daniel Spoerri to Robert Filliou. Accession #s: 04.01 (Box 70, Folder I.1154)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1976, undated; Photocopies of documents concerning Daniel Spoerri. Accession #s: 96.18 (Box 70, Folder I.1155)
  - Daniel Spoerri, undated; Bag of Danish baking powder with Galerie Køpcke "Attention Oeuvre d'Art" stamp. Accession #s: 04.01 (Box 70, Folder I.1156)
  - Daniel Spoerri, undated; Photocopies, copy photographs, and transparencies of works, mostly 31 Variations on a Meal(ca. 1965), produced by the collection for publication use, with collection notes. (Box 70, Folder I.1157)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1961-1963, 1971-1979, undated; News clippings, ephemera, and articles acquired from estate of Hans Hartmann. (Box 70, Folder I.1158)
  - Daniel Spoerri, 1963; Announcement and menu for Restaurant de la Galerie J. (Box 70, Folder I.1159)
  - Elka Spoerri, 2002; Obituary by Roberta Smith in The New York Times(6/3/2002). (Box 71, Folder I.1160)
  - Karlheinz Stockhausen, 1961; Originale(1961), including notes from Laurence Alloway and color copy of score annotated by Arthur Caspari. Accession #s:[00.14] (Box 71, Folder I.1161)
  - Johannes Stttgen, 1968; "Deutsche studentenpartei," 1 page. (Box 71, Folder I.1162)
  - Sonia Švecov, 1967; Correspondence to Ken Friedman with paper flower and stalk of pussy willow (3/20/1967). (Box 71, Folder I.1163)
  - Harald Szeemann, 1970; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, mostly regarding Happening & Fluxus, Klnischer Kunstverein, Cologne. (Box 71, Folder I.1164)
  - Harald Szeemann, 1969-1970; Correspondence to Arthur Køpcke. (Box 71, Folder I.1165)
  - Tamas Szentjóby, 1972-1973, undated; Photocopies of correspondence to Ken Friedman, with photographs from performance "Sit-Out"(1972) with notes for publication; photocopies of Ken Friedman's notes; notes by Hendricks. Originals are with the Museum Collection. (Box 71, Folder I.1166)
  - William Tarr, 1972-1974; "Ideas for Artists," including correspondence sent to Larry Miller. Inventory #s: 05712, 05711.1-2, 05713.1-3 (Box 71, Folder I.1167)
  - Andr Thomkins, 1969, 1971, 1979, 1986; Exhibition announcements. Accession #s: 94.08 (Box 71, Folder I.1168)
  - Jean Tinguely, 1961; News clippings acquired from estate of Hans Hartmann. (Box 71, Folder I.1169)
  - Jean Tinguely, 1973; Postcard to Arthur Køpcke. (Box 71, Folder I.1170)
  - Raša Todosijevi, 1975; Pamphlet, "The Edinburgh Statement." (Box 71, Folder I.1171)
  - Yasunao Tone, [1962], 1977, 2003-2004, undated; Flyer for "one man show," [Minami Gallery, 1962], 2 copies; letter to Hendricks with enclosed article by Yasunao Tone, "John Cage and Recording" (2004); "Tone's assessment of Tono," with note from Hendricks (2004); polaroid photograph of Yasunao Tone by Robert Watts (1977); photocopies and negative transparencies of works and portrait, produced by the collection for publication use, with collection notes. Inventory #s: 01740 (Box 71, Folder I.1172)
  - Endre Tt, 1972-1976, 1982; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, including artist's book "TOTal Joys" (1971-75). (Box 71, Folder I.1173)
  - Endre Tt, 1973; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, including copies of various letters originally sent to others. (Box 71, Folder I.1174)
  - Endre Tt, 1971-1979; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, including "1/2 dozen Berliner gladness postcards (1973-1978)" and ephemera. (Box 71, Folder I.1175)
  - Endre Tt, 1971-1977; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, including various pamphlets and letters to Eleanor Ballou; artist's books "Incomplete Informations (Verbal & Visual)" (1972) and "The States of Zero" (1971). (Box 71, Folder I.1176)
  - Endre Tt, 1972-1974; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, including artist's books "Possessive Adjective" (1972) and "On the next page I shall say something" (1973); set of postcards/ephemera "Absolute possessive pronouns" (1972). (Box 71, Folder I.1177)
  - Jiř Valoch, 1969-1970; Correspondence to Ken Friedman, including pamphlets by the artist "bsne pro pozorovn reality" (1969) and "8 sonnets" (1969). (Box 72, Folder I.1178)
  - Jiř Valoch, 1969-1970; Correspondence to Ken Friedman. (Box 72, Folder I.1179)
  - Peter Van Beveren, 1975-1976; Ephemera. (Box 72, Folder I.1180)
  - Jan Van Der Mark, 1970-1972; 1 of 4 files on Wolf Vostell, including correspondence (including with Wolf Vostell and Dick Higgins); news clippings; programs; flyers; installation photographs. Topics covered include Wolf Vostell's Salat installation (1970);Happenings & Fluxus exhibition. In English and German. Accession #s: 01.01 (Box 72, Folder I.1181)
  - Jan Van Der Mark, 1970-1972; 2 of 4 files on Wolf Vostell, including correspondence (including with Wolf Vostell and Dick Higgins); news clippings; programs; flyers; installation photographs. Topics covered include Wolf Vostell's Salat installation (1970);Happenings & Fluxus exhibitition. In English and German. Accession #s: 01.01 (Box 72, Folder I.1182)
  - Jan Van Der Mark, 1970-1972; 3 of 4 files on Wolf Vostell, including correspondence (including with Wolf Vostell and Dick Higgins); news clippings; programs; flyers; installation photographs. Topics covered include Wolf Vostell's Salat installation (1970);Happenings & Fluxus exhibitition. In English and German. Accession #s: 01.01 (Box 72, Folder I.1183)
  - Jan Van Der Mark, 1970-1972; 4 of 4 files on Wolf Vostell, including correspondence (including with Wolf Vostell and Dick Higgins); news clippings; programs; flyers; installation photographs. Topics covered include Wolf Vostell's Salat installation (1970);Happenings & Fluxus exhibit. In English and German. Accession #s: 01.01 (Box 72, Folder I.1184)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964; Collection photocopies of "lettre a Maciunas contenant Idees Divers" or "letter to Maciunas" (see I.1186-I.1189 for original). (Box 72, Folder I.1185)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; 1 of 4 folders of "lettre a Maciunas contenant Idees Divers" or "letter to Maciunas," 113-page letter, regarding ideas and plans for works, performances, festivals, and including sketches, collage, and works, with later notes (likely added at the time of acquisition by the Silvermans). Silverman #s:<427.I (Box 72, Folder I.1186)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; 2 of 4 folders of "lettre a Maciunas contenant Idees Divers" or "letter to Maciunas," 113-page letter, regarding ideas and plans for works, performances, festivals, and including sketches, collage, and works, with later notes (likely added at the time of acquisition by the Silvermans). Silverman #s:<427.I (Box 72, Folder I.1187)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; 3 of 4 folders of "lettre a Maciunas contenant Idees Divers" or "letter to Maciunas," 113-page letter, regarding ideas and plans for works, performances, festivals, and including sketches, collage, and works, with later notes (likely added at the time of acquisition by the Silvermans). Silverman #s:<427.I (Box 72, Folder I.1188)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; 4 of 4 folders of "lettre a Maciunas contenant Idees Divers" or "letter to Maciunas," 113-page letter, regarding ideas and plans for works, performances, festivals, and including sketches, collage, and works, with later notes (likely added at the time of acquisition by the Silvermans). Silverman #s:<427.I (Box 72, Folder I.1189)
  - Ben Vautier, 1966; ALS Ben Vautier - Milan Knžk (10/1966). Inventory #s: 02867 (Box 72, Folder I.1190)
  - Ben Vautier, 1966-1967, undated; 5 ALS Ben Vautier - Milan Knžk and Sonia Švecov. Inventory #s: 02859, 02921, 02922, 02933 (Box 72, Folder I.1191)
  - Ben Vautier, 1966-1967; 2 ALS Ben Vautier - Milan Knžk; "L'Art n'est Plus Nouveau" mimeographed text in French, with autograph translation into Czech. Inventory #s: 02924, 02925, 02926.1-2 (Box 72, Folder I.1192)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967; 1 ALS and 6 empty envelopes Ben Vautier - Milan Knžk. Inventory #s: 02927.1-7 (Box 72, Folder I.1193)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; 1 ALS Ben Vautier - Alison Knowles. Accession #s: 89.03 (Box 72, Folder I.1194)
  - Ben Vautier, 1972; Package of texts, announcements, posters and works sent to Jonas Mekas (9/23/1972), including Postman's Choice(1965 version). (Box 72, Folder I.1195)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964; Photocopies of correspondence to and from Rudolf Pereboom and Stanley Brouwn regarding plans for an exhibition at Amstel 47, Amsterdam. (Box 72, Folder I.1196)
  - Ben Vautier, [1964]; Correspondence to Rudolf Pereboom and Stanley Brouwn regarding plans for an exhibition at Amstel 47, Amsterdam. Includes photographs of works for exhibition. Accession #s: 03.06 (Box 72, Folder I.1197)
  - Ben Vautier, 1963; Empty record sleeve for Disque de Musique Total, "15 compositions musicales pour la recherche et l'enseignement d'une musique - total - en hommage John Cage." Inventory #s: 02929 (Box 72, Folder I.1198)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; Includes "L'art total communique;" photocopy of Rotterdam fluxus festival announcement; scrapbooked copy of untitled "nine directions for art" booklet; other announcements. Inventory #s: 01780, [01781], [01782], 01783, 01784, [01787]. (Box 73, Folder I.1199)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967, undated; Announcements, mailings, postcards works, and other text works, including for exhibitions and events at Galerie Ben Doute de Tout, Nice. Includes Postman's Choice(1967 Fluxus version). In French and English. Inventory #s: 02928.1-14 (Box 73, Folder I.1200)
  - Ben Vautier, 1962, 1966-1968, undated; Announcements, mailings, postcard works, and other text works, including for exhibitions and events at Galerie Ben Doute de Tout, Nice, including mailings to Ken Friedman. Includes "Certificate of Presence Delivered as Work of Art" (1967); letter to Ken Friedman on back of announcement for "Hall des Remises en Question." In French and English. Inventory #s: 05415, 05413, 05423, 054291.-2, 05430, 05427.1-2, 05426, 05428.5, 05431, 05432.1, 05433.1-2, 05434 (Box 73, Folder I.1201)
  - Ben Vautier, 1965, 1967, 1973, 1983; Cards and announcements, including 3 versions of Postman's Choice(1965, 1967, 1973; 1973 version addressed to Ken Friedman and Richard Foreman). Inventory #s: 05386.1-3, 05385.1-4 (Box 73, Folder I.1202)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967; "La Bonne Journee," invitation ("Fluxus Nice") and written description of event in French. Inventory #s: 05424.1-2 (Box 73, Folder I.1203)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967; "Le IVe Festival de la Libre Expression" presented by Jean-Jacques Lebel, Saint-Tropez; announcement/program and poster mailed to Ken Friedman, in French. Inventory #s: 05425.1-3 (Box 73, Folder I.1204)
  - Ben Vautier, 1966-1967, undated; Texts, works and other documents, photocopy and original, including concerning Galerie Ben Doute de Tout, in French; photcopy of Maciunas's notes on Ben Vautier from Jean Brown Archive. Inventory #s:[01839], 05383 (Box 73, Folder I.1205)
  - Ben Vautier, 1962-1967, 1974; Announcements, programs, texts, works, posters, notes, and other documents, including for concerts and exhibitions, and concerning Galerie Ben Doute de Tout and the "Festival de la Libre Expression," acquired from Ben Vautier. In French and English. Inventory #s: 01786.1-24 (Box 73, Folder I.1206)
  - Ben Vautier, 1973-1974, undated; "Pour et Contre," texts and interviews concerning exhibitions, including of Olivier Mosset and Marcel Alocco, in French; "On Social Recognition" by Henry Flynt. Inventory #s: 05387.1-3 (Box 73, Folder I.1207)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Various mimeograph documents and texts, formerly held by Maciunas. In French. (Box 73, Folder I.1208)
  - Ben Vautier, 1971; "Ben contre Support Surface et Tel Quel (pour le plaisir)," 4 pages. In French. (Box 73, Folder I.1209)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; "Programme des 7 Jours," La Troupe D'Art Total; form letter to Ray Johnson, regarding "John Cage Aux Baux;" program for "John Cage Aux Baux;" "Fluxus 1964" announcement, annotated by Albert Fine. In French, with collection notes. Inventory #s: 05533, 05535, 05536, 05537 (Box 73, Folder I.1210)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Photocopies of postcard works from the Tate Gallery Archive. (Box 73, Folder I.1211)
  - Ben Vautier, 1993-1994; "Lettre de Ben aux Peuples Inquiets,"Lettre no. 5, 1994; "Real Bull shit 0," 1993. (Box 73, Folder I.1212)
  - Ben Vautier, [ca. 1971-1972]; Text (or possibly newsletter), including descriptions of exhibitions and other events in Nice and elsewhere, 9 pages, in French. (Box 73, Folder I.1213)
  - Ben Vautier, 1966; "A L'Occasion de L'Exposition D'Arman au Musee Municipal de Saint-Paul-De-Venice," 2 texts. Inventory #s: 05408.1-2 (Box 73, Folder I.1214)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Document cover with notes by Ben Vautier. (Box 73, Folder I.1215)
  - Ben Vautier, 1960s, 1970, 1984, undated; "Invitation une Exposition" (1970), "Open Tout and Close Nothing;" "Chronique Touche a Tout de Ben;" Tout No. 1 (1968), 2 copies; "Galerie Ben Doute De Tout Presente," collected programs, texts, and other documents; "minable culture" (1984). (Box 73, Folder I.1216)
  - Ben Vautier, 1969; "Stencils de Ben," unbound book of collected mimeographs (including programs, announcements, and other documents), 1963-1969. (Box 73, Folder I.1217)
  - Ben Vautier, [1960]; "Rdaction au Laboratoire 32," bound booklet. Inventory #s: 01788 (Box 73, Folder I.1218)
  - Ben Vautier, 1963-1967; "Galerie Ben Doute De Tout Presente," collected programs. Inventory #s: 01789 (Box 73, Folder I.1219)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, undated; Programs, including "Programme des 7 Jours," and other documents enclosed in a folder made from a cropped poster. Inventory #s: 01790 (Box 73, Folder I.1220)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Collection inventory of "Je Tourneau" manuscript (manuscript not here). (Box 73, Folder I.1221)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "esthetique definitif et preuves," typed and autograph annotated manuscript, with collection inventory of pages. Inventory #s: 05464 (Box 73, Folder I.1222)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "esthetique broullon [?] el double," typed and autograph annotated manuscript, with collection inventory of pages. Inventory #s: 05465 (Box 74, Folder I.1223)
  - Ben Vautier, 1968; "Moi, Ben, Je Signe"/"chapitre mor [?] Ben Je Signe - Tel quel Donne a l'Imprimeur," typed and autograph annotated manuscript. Inventory #s: 05466.1-2 (Box 74, Folder I.1224)
  - Ben Vautier, 1968; "Double Theatre de Comportement Taut sur une page," annotated manuscript. Inventory #s: 05467 (Box 74, Folder I.1225)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "Chap. Mor [?] Ben je signe Tape an Anglais et sur feuille jaune," pages scrapbooked with typed texts (possibly manuscript for publication). Inventory #s: 05468 (Box 74, Folder I.1226)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Untitled scrapbooked, collaged, and autograph manuscript. Inventory #s: 05469 (Box 74, Folder I.1227)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "Theatre 3," typed and autograph annotated manuscript. Inventory #s: 05470 (Box 74, Folder I.1228)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "cinema 7," 2 pages of notes (possibly manuscript for publication). Inventory #s: 05471 (Box 74, Folder I.1229)
  - Ben Vautier, 1982; Copy of "excommunication" document. Inventory #s: 05472 (Box 74, Folder I.1230)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Photocopies of and collection notes on the "Idea Book." Inventory #s:[01026] (Box 74, Folder I.1231)
  - Ben Vautier, 1988; Notes and mock-up for version of Propositions for One Page used in publication Fluxus: selections from the Gilbert and Lila Silverman Collection, by Clive Phillpot and Jon Hendricks. New York, N.Y.: The Museum of Modern Art, 1988. Inventory #s: 05388.1-15 (Box 74, Folder I.1232)
  - Ben Vautier, 1971, 1974; Flash Art 23 (April 1971), "special issue on Ben"; "Mon actuelle position en art" statement, with 9 slides of the artist's work. (Box 74, Folder I.1233)
  - Ben Vautier, [1964], 1975; News clippings, including "Quer ist Ben?" Inventory #s: 05532 (Box 74, Folder I.1234)
  - Ben Vautier, 1991, 2003; Announcement for lecture by the artist at Emily Harvey Gallery, New York, 1991, 2 copies; nnouncement for "Ben's Bizart Bazart," Galerie Daniel Templon, Paris, 2003, 2 copies. (Box 74, Folder I.1235)
  - Ben Vautier, [ca. 1960s]; 15 photographs by Ben Vautier of an art exhibition, acquired from Milan Knžk. Inventory #s: 03588.1-15 (Box 74, Folder I.1236)
  - Ben Vautier, [ca. 1960s]; 10 photographs of works by Ben Vautier, acquired from Milan Knžk. Inventory #s: 03587.1-10 (Box 74, Folder I.1237)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967; Copies of announcement for event by Annie Vautier, "Annie shall expose some pots of flowers" In French and English. (Box 74, Folder I.1238)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Polaroid photographs of Ben Vautier works in the collection. Inventory #s:[05474-05504], [05506-05529] Accession #s:[91.04] (Box 74, Folder I.1239)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Photocopies, copy photographs, and transparencies of works, produced by the collection for publication use, with collection notes. (Box 74, Folder I.1240)
  - Ben Vautier, 1959, 1961, 1964, undated; Copy of program for 7 Jours de Recherche,"Premiere partie de la representation" (1964); note to Maciunas; copies of documents from Sculptures Vivantes. Inventory #s:[05528.1-4] (Box 74, Folder I.1241)
  - Ben Vautier, 1965; "Cinquante propositions pour une page" ("Fifty propositions for a page"), typescript ("original carbon copy"). Accession #s: 01.02 (Box 74, Folder I.1242)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967, 1979; Ccontact sheets by Marcel Alocco of events/performances in Nice. Accession #s: 94.24 (Box 74, Folder I.1243)
  - Ben Vautier, 1962-1963, 1974, 1994, undated; Includes ephemera, "Pour ou Contre" (1974). Acquired from estate of Hans Hartmann. Vinyl record, "Musique = aussi absence de musique"/"Creation et audition privees" (1963) was removed from this folder and transferred to the Museum Collection. (Box 75, Folder I.1244)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967, undated; Includes ephemera, newsletters, cards, mailings, and various materials acquired from estate of Hans Hartmann. (Box 75, Folder I.1245)
  - Ben Vautier, 1963-1967, undated; Includes ephemera, newsletters, mailings, texts, and works acquired from estate of Hans Hartmann. (Box 75, Folder I.1246)
  - Ben Vautier, 1963-1967, undated; Includes newsletters, mailings, texts, and works acquired from estate of Hans Hartmann. (Box 75, Folder I.1247)
  - Ben Vautier, 1973; Une Lettre de la Fenetre, no. 1 (1973), sent to Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05410.1-4 (Box 75, Folder I.1248)
  - Ben Vautier, 1968; "Open Tout and close nothing," 1 long sheet, folded. (Box 75, Folder I.1249)
  - Ben Vautier, 1978; "A Letter from Berlin," 6 pages. Inventory #s: 04885.1-3 (Box 75, Folder I.1250)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "A Little Book of Ben," booklet by Reflection Press. Inventory #s: 05327 (Box 75, Folder I.1251)
  - Ben Vautier, 1974; "After DADA my position on art is" text with letter to Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05328 (Box 75, Folder I.1252)
  - Ben Vautier, 1979-1982; "Annie on my mind," booklet mailed to Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05329.1-3 (Box 75, Folder I.1253)
  - Ben Vautier, 1978; "Any stupid ideas just as they come and go," book edition. Inventory #s: 05330 (Box 75, Folder I.1254)
  - Ben Vautier, 1981-1983, 1991; Artists' pamphlets. Inventory #s: 05335.1-8 (Box 75, Folder I.1255)
  - Ben Vautier, 196701970, undated; Texts; ephemera; exhibition announcements. Inventory #s: 05336.1-3, 05343, 05344.1-2, 05351 (Box 75, Folder I.1256)
  - Ben Vautier, 1965-1971, 1982, undated; Texts, newsletters, and ephemera, including "Flux manifesto" postcards designed by Maciunas; special issue of Flash Art on the artist (4/1971). Inventory #s: 05353.1-3, 05362, 05363, 05364, 05365, 05368.1-2, 05369, 05352 (Box 75, Folder I.1257)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Re-editions of "Moi Ben je signe" and "Tout No..," sent to Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05372.1-2 (Box 75, Folder I.1258)
  - Ben Vautier, 1965; "(1) Receive (2) Return" postcard, designed by Maciunas for Fluxus, 3 copies. Inventory #s: 05374 (Box 75, Folder I.1259)
  - Ben Vautier, 1970-1971; Ephemera for exhibitions and events at La Galerie Ben Doute de Tout. Inventory #s: 05437, 05438, 05439, 05440, 05441, 05443, 05444, 05445 (Box 75, Folder I.1260)
  - Ben Vautier, 1971; "Les Paravents," exhibition ephemera. Inventory #s: 05446.1-3 (Box 75, Folder I.1261)
  - Ben Vautier, 1972, 1982-1983; Exhibition ephemera. Inventory #s: 05447.1-2, 05448.1-4, 05449, 05450, 05451 (Box 75, Folder I.1262)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967, undated; Correspondence and ephemera sent to Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05453.1-3, 05454, 05455.1-2 (Box 75, Folder I.1263)
  - Ben Vautier, 1967; Mailing to Arthur Køpcke, including collages, clippings, and notes. Inventory #s: 05456 (Box 75, Folder I.1264)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "Photo de Ben," advertisement with photograph of the artist. Inventory #s: 05376.1-2 (Box 75, Folder I.1265)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "Liste personelle d'appreciations sur Ben," 1 page. Inventory #s: 05370 (Box 75, Folder I.1266)
  - Ben Vautier, 1962, undated; Newsletters and announcements, Inventory #s: 05371, 05367, 05366.1-2 (Box 75, Folder I.1267)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; Postcard work ("I Ben declare that the following signature"), 2 addressed copies. Inventory #s: 05361 (Box 75, Folder I.1268)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "Fourre Tout No. 1 Contenu (dans aucun ordre)," packet of materials by Fluxus artists, 2 copies, mailed to Ken Friedman and Dick Higgins and Alison Knowles. Inventory #s: 05356.1-2 (Box 76, Folder I.1269)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964-1967, undated; Newsletters; announcements; ephemera; mailing to Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05355, 05350, 05348, 05347.1-2, 05346, 05345.1-3 (Box 76, Folder I.1270)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964; Piece n 33 mailed to Jonas Mekas ("I mean to kill George Brecht). (Box 76, Folder I.1271)
  - Ben Vautier, 1968, 1967-1972; Correspondence to Arthur Køpcke (1/10/1968) and Ken Friedman. Inventory #s: 05460, 05461 (Box 76, Folder I.1272)
  - Ben Vautier, 1964, 1972, 1985; Oversized materials: "My Statement for Documenta 5" (from flash art, 1972),Arts Graphiques 3 (1985), hand-written poster for Quelquechose (1964). (Box 411, Folder I.1273*)
  - Ben Vautier, undated; "Fluxus repertoire" books, 2 binders with hand-written and printed Fluxus scores organized by last name of artist. Marks next to scores may indicate works performed by Ben Vautier. According to note by Hendricks, "These 2 books were used by Vautier for performance and are the basis for a planned book of Fluxus scores." Binders are housed in cardboard box annotated by Ben Vautier. Inventory #s: 01027 (Box 77, Folder I.1274)
  - William Vazan, undated; Texts, ephemera, map, and other documents relating to World Line. (Box 76, Folder I.1275)